Hey Carson, it kind of feels like this
came about pretty quickly. Uh how how
did what what's the path that leads to
today?
>> Yeah, it's been a it's been quite the
journey. Um
we kind of knew uh maybe beginning of my
basketball season that we were going to
explore this. Um but you know, we were
trying to figure out the right way to go
about it um and the most fruitful way to
do it. Um, so it's been it's been a it's
been a cool journey. Um, I was out at
the combine a couple weeks ago with um
my agents, Jack Becka and Jack Tab. So,
not not doing workouts cuz I was in the
middle of basketball season with Notre
Dame, but um just for meetings with
teams and meeting the some of these guys
out here. So, um it's been quite the
journey so far and man, it's just
getting started. So, I'm excited to see
where where we can all go.
>> James
Along those lines, Carson, uh, what
gives you the confidence that you can
make the transition from basketball to I
mean to football? And have you ever
played football before?
>> I've never played football before. No.
Um,
I think just an awareness of my physical
gifts uh that that were showcased on the
the basketball floor.
Um, and I think this sport honors those
gifts and the things that got me to
Notre Dame and got me uh carried me
through my career and the things I pride
myself on. think this sport honors those
things and um you know my frame, how I
developed
um h how I developed as a player, kind
of like my play style and and what I
what I what I pride myself on, you know,
rebounding, you know, a couple years ago
leading the country in rebounding and
this year leading the ACC in offensive
rebounding. I I pride myself on dirty
work and rebounding and being physical.
So I think football almost honors those
a little bit better than basketball
does. So, uh, that's why we're here
today.
>> Nathan, go ahead.
>> Carson, along those same lines, you said
that, um, around the start of this
season, this was something that you
thought you might entertain. What What
brought this on? I know you said that
you haven't played football in high
school or college. Hadn't um, what what
led you to ultimately a feel like this
was something you wanted to do and felt
like something you could do?
Yeah, I've had the itch to play football
uh pretty much all through college and
really really growing up. Um in high
school, I was real small though. Uh I
didn't hit, you know, growth spurts till
late. I didn't have armpit hair till
late in high school. So I was kind of a
late bloomer in that way. And um
so I never really thought about it too
much, gave it too much thought and and
attention until
my freshman year of college when I kind
of started bulking up and realized,
okay, this is probably my max height and
uh I got a good frame on me. Um and I
take care of my body well. So kind of
started thinking about it then and
thought about dual sporting a lot every
year. Uh but it never really made sense
in college because my my basketball
career just I kept climbing and um
getting better there. So, I wanted to
give my focus and attention to that. And
then it just kind of worked out where my
basketball career has has come to a an
end in college and, you know, it's
perfect timing to kind of segue into
this transition and uh that's what we're
doing.
>> And then one quick follow up there. You
said that you had some thoughts about
dual, you know, playing dual sports.
What how close did you get to um
exploring that at all when you were um
playing college basketball?
Yeah, I mean we we had talks uh while I
was in the portal with my compliance at
Northern Arizona. Um
and we figured out that I I didn't have
football eligibility this last year. Um
so it ended up making it an easy
decision to uh just play basketball. Um
and uh yeah, so but we came we came
pretty close. you know, we explored
those options, but I think it had to do
with some clock timing where I didn't
have any eligibility left in college.
>> Gotcha. Thanks.
>> Yeah.
>> Um,
obviously, you know, Colts have had Moi
Cox here now for a long time. He's he's
a former basketball player. Um, do you
know his story? Do you know him?
Anything?
>> Yeah, I know his story. I actually uh
called with Mo
maybe
I want to say it was it was late last
year, maybe November, December. Um, when
we kind of knew we were going down this
path, I uh I reached out to him. I DM'd
him. He DM'd me right back. Follow me
back. DM me right back and and he said,
"Dude, yeah, let's hop on a call." So,
we we talked for probably half an hour
and uh he just I just wanted to hear his
experience. I wanted to hear his his
journey, how he did it. um how he
navigated the the the spot I was in then
and then you know the spot I'm in now
and and just how he went about the
process and um I hear nothing but
unbelievable things about Mo. So I'm
excited to officially meet him in in
person and and uh get to working with
him cuz you can't get a better success
story in and the most recent success
story. So to be in this building with
with th that caliber of a dude and these
caliber of coaches who who have done it
um is a blessing and uh I'm aware of
that and excited to be a part of it.
>> What what was your I mean I'm sure you
had a ton of takeaways from from Mo on
on making the transition, but is there
is there one that kind of like sticks
out?
Let me think back to our conversation.
I think the the uh the coolest thing and
and uh Tom Manning said it too. He's
like we we had to teach Mo everything,
you know? He didn't he didn't know
anything just like you you don't know
much about football. So, um I think it
was just cool to hear like, okay, he's
actually in, you know, you hear the
story and you're like, okay, maybe he's
in a different position. No, like he
actually had to start from from uh
square one, too. So, I thought that was
um special and and um you know, can
relate to that. Um but no, just his his
energy on the call. I more more so any
than anything you said just his energy
and his enthusiasm and his excitement
just to to talk to me and hear about the
story um was cool.
>> And last question, Stephen.
>> Hey Carson, so uh you mentioned that you
had been thinking about this for a long
time and maybe started putting some
things in motion a while back. What does
that look like? I mean, cuz if you just
pick up the phone and start calling NFL,
if your agent or whoever starts, you
know, picks up the phone and starts
calling NFL teams, why would they listen
to you? I mean, how did you make the
case? And how did that how did how did
the belief come about from them that you
could do this or I don't know, maybe it
was pre-existing, I don't know.
>> Yeah, I actually just um started looking
up who represents who uh in the football
world. um just kind of doing my due
diligence from trying to find an agent,
you know, someone who can understand the
story, believe in me, and then, you
know, make it happen. So, I ended up uh
reaching out to JB Sports um with Jack
Becka and Jack Tab and those guys and uh
I mean, they just they just had Caleb
Loner, who um I'm sure the football
world, you guys know him, uh dual
sported at Utah, and Broncos took him, I
think it was the seventh round. So, they
just did it, they just did it the year
before. um little bit different scenario
with him playing, but um and you know
they have a bunch of huge names um with
very successful careers in the NFL. So
um he he he he told me on the first call
too, he's like, "Dude, I'll do this till
I die." You know, I love this stuff. So,
um, he was excited when I reached out,
you know, we hopped on a phone call for
a while and, um, with both of them, with
both the Jackson, uh, and we got to
talking and they saw my film and and
everything. And then, um, you know, we
kind of just went from there.
>> And then I, this is like a procedural
thing. It's probably not even, you're
not the best person to ask, but like you
don't have to go through the draft in
this scenario, right? Is that how that
works?
>> No, I'm Yeah, I'm not uh, draft
eligible. So,
>> draft eligible. Okay.
>> Free agent. So it made all of this
possible.